

Julio Cesar Ramirez Paredes

Profile

Bachelor of civil engineering, expert in engineering solutions for fluid mechanics and computational fluid dynamics in challenging problems. Interest in fluid mechanics and programming languages. Outstanding learning capacity, motivation to continue learning and orientation to achieve results in my career.

Social Network

Mz. C1 Lt. 26

- **♀** Mario Cavagnaro Bellavista, Callao
- **(**+51) 939196012
- ✓ julio.ramirez@pucp.edu.pe
- illio.ramirez
- juliocesar-ramirez
- in julio-cesar-ramirez-paredes
- juliocesar-ramirez.github.io

Languages

English Portuguese

Programming

C++ Fortran

Python

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering

San Miguel ,PE Jul 2019

Work Experience

Hidro Mayu

Huacho, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

- Fluid mechanics and open channel hydraulics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students of the equipment of the Universidad Nacional José Faustino Sánchez Carrión's hyrdraulics laboratory
- Centro de Investigación y Tecnología del Agua Barranco, PE Research Assistant Sep 2019 - Nov 2021
 - Urban air quality: Numerical simulation of the navier equations for incompresible newtonian flow in air fluid in urban environments using Openfoam.
 - o Dam break: Numerical modeling of the shallow water equation for incompresible newtonian flow in dam break escenarios using Telemac-2D.
- Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnologia Barranco, PE Teaching Assistant Aug 2019 - Nov 2021
 - o Mathematics III: Solid understanding of linear algebra and numerical methods.
- Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú San Miguel, PE Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 Teaching Assistant
 - o Open Channel Hydraulics: Solid understanding of channel morphology, hydraulic engineering and sediment transport.
- MJ & Asociados Water Resources Consulting Lima, PE PractitionerMar 2019 - Jun 2019
 - River flood: Observation of flood zone in the Moquegua river under extreme flood condition to investigate the resilience of the infrastructure.

PROYECTS

- Turbulent parabolic velocity: Development of a new boundary condition in the Openfoam library, based on c++. Vertical profile from a predefined parabolic velocity with randoms fluctuations over the time. This pertubations allow to work with LES and DES in unsteady flows.
- Convert STL format to XYZ: Code in fortran that allows to take a mesh in STL format and generate an XYZ file. The elements of XYZ file can be used in programs such as qgis, excel, blukenue.
- Turbulent schmidt number with scalar transport equation: Implementation of the scalar dissipation equation for a pollutnat with the parameters of the schmidt y prandtl number. Code in Openfoam, based on c++.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, Fortran, Python, R, Bash y Lisp
- Emacs, Pointwise, Tecplot, Qgis, Telemac, Openfoam, Blender, Latex, Ubuntu, Git y Aws.
- **Tiping**: Typing speed of 65 wpm Monkeytype, Keybr.

Extra-curricular Activities

- Summer Work and Travel program 2015: California y Utah.
- Member of Gemra Pucp 2018 y 2019